hey everybody welcome to this a2
english listening practice video you can
use
this video to practice your listening
and comprehension
as i speak before we start
remember to subscribe to the channel
click on the bell
and follow us on instagram you ready
[Music]
so today i'm gonna talk about stress
this might not be the funnest topic
but it's definitely an important one
we all feel stressed sometimes whether
it's
every day or just once in a while
but nobody is stress free
first let's talk about some of the main
causes of stress in our lives
and then we'll talk a little bit about
how to relieve
stress so the first thing that comes to
mind
when talking about stress is work
for most adults work is a mandatory
responsibility
even if you're a stay-at-home mom your
daily life
is full of work one of the elements
of the workday that causes stress
is the commute the word commute refers
to the journey
to and from work for people that live in
big
cities their commute can be long
and stressful i've talked to people
before
who have told me that it takes them two
hours to get to work
and two hours to get home i can't
imagine
having that kind of commute i would hate
being stuck in traffic every morning
and evening how about you how long
is your commute to work another reason
why our work can stress us out
is because we have deadlines
deadlines are time limits for finishing
work for example many workers
have deadlines for all their projects
and if they don't meet their deadlines
they get in trouble deadlines are
especially hard
for people who procrastinate people who
procrastinate
don't start their work until the
deadline is
very near this can cause a lot of
pressure for workers
because they need to work really hard
and really
fast okay another source of stress
in people's lives is their relationships
of course relationships usually bring
positive things to our lives
but when it comes to relationships there
are
always difficulties one great example of
this
is marriage being married is
definitely a challenge you have to work
together
as a team you have to communicate well
and you have to solve problems this
isn't easy
there are always going to be arguments
miscommunications
and plenty of other difficulties and
when you
experience these things in your marriage
it's definitely stressful
one other relationship that can be
stressful is your relationship
with your children children go through
many phases when they grow up and it's
not
easy to deal with these changes
it's hard for children and for parents
as children deal with changes in their
lives
they often make mistakes parents
have to help their children learn from
their mistakes
and they have to teach them and guide
them
needless to say this can be really
stressful
all right now let's talk about how to
de-stress
when we feel stressed because of our
work
there are several ways we can relieve
that
stress one of the best ways to do this
is to exercise when we exercise
we can take our mind off of work
also exercising releases endorphins
in the brain endorphins are chemicals
that give you a positive feeling it
feels
good to exercise and you usually
feel relaxed afterwards another way to
de-stress
is to spend time with your family
for example i like to play board games
with my family
which allows me to have fun and relax a
little bit
one other thing i like to do to
de-stress
is read when you read you can forget
about
all the stressful things in your life
and you can escape for a little bit
reading is a great tool to relieve
stress
if you're feeling stressed out from
certain relationships
in your life one of the best ways to
relieve this stress is to communicate
how you're feeling if you're able to
talk to your spouse
or children or whoever it is
about your issues this can help you
improve your relationships and feel less
stressed
all right now i'm gonna ask you some
questions
about today's video to see how well
you understood number one what are
deadlines number two what happens
when children deal with changes in their
lives
and number three what's one way to
de-stress
okay remember to subscribe to the
channel
click on the bell and follow us on
instagram
for more english tips and lessons i'll
see you next time
[Music]